so now that we have seen an example of
open trolling let's do a loop unrolling
quiz let's say we have the following
loop we load something from memory we
add it to some sort of a sum in r3 and
then we move our memory pointer by 4
bytes and then if we have reached some
end of an array then we exit otherwise
we loop back so what this loop is really
doing is its summing up an array let's
say we have a processor that is in order
and executes one instruction per cycle a
load takes 3 cycles so for example here
because we are using the result of the
load there would be two stall cycles in
between and add or add I take two cycles
each so for example between the add I
and the branch there would be one stall
cycle so the question for you is after
scheduling this loop but without
applying any unrolling it takes how many
cycles to do a thousand iterations of
the loop and then after unrolling ones
meaning we do the work of two of these
iterations per new iteration and then
scheduling the loop it takes how many
cycles for a thousand iterations